School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Cornell University

office: 471-B Rhodes Hall, Ithaca, NY 14853 phone: 908-635-4044 email: clt67@cornell.edu

web: http://www.csl.cornell.edu/~ctorng last updated: February 2019

### **Research Interests**

I am interested in all aspects of computer architecture, especially specialized systems that are co-designed across software, architecture, and VLSI to unify emerging applications with emerging technologies. In the future, I hope to engage experts across software (e.g., AR, VR, intelligence on the edge, smart healthcare) and technology (e.g., TFETs, emerging memories, energy harvesting) to continue a track of cross-stack research.

### **Education**

Eddeliton	
• Cornell University, Ithaca, NY Ph.D. Candidate in Electrical and Computer Engineering Advisor: Professor Christopher Batten, Expected Graduation: Spring 2019 Tentative Thesis: Software, Architecture, and VLSI/Circuit Co-Design for Task-Based Para	2012 – Present allel Runtimes
• Cornell University, Ithaca, NY B.S Electrical Engineering and Computer Science	2008 – 2012
Awards and Honors	
<ul> <li>Rising Stars in Computer Architecture (RISC-A)</li> <li>IEEE Micro Top Pick from Hot Chips (for Hot Chips '17 paper)</li> <li>NSF GRFP Honorable Mention</li> <li>Finalist for Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship (QInF)</li> <li>H.C. Torng Fellowship – Cornell one-semester graduate fellowship (no familial relation)</li> </ul>	2018 2018 2014 2013 2012
Research Experience	
• Software, Architecture, and VLSI Co-Design for Task-Based Parallel Runtimes Computer Systems Laboratory, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY Advisor: Professor Christopher Batten	2016 – Present
• Methodologies for Rapid ASIC Design  Computer Systems Laboratory, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY  Advisors/Mentors: Professor Christopher Batten (Cornell University)  Advisors/Mentors: Professor Michael B. Taylor (University of Washington)  Advisors/Mentors: Professor Ronald G. Dreslinski (University of Michigan)  Advisors/Mentors: Brucek Khailany (NVIDIA Research)	2016 – Present
• Architecture and Circuit Co-Design for Integrated Voltage Regulation Computer Systems Laboratory, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY Advisors/Mentors: Professor Christopher Batten Advisors/Mentors: Professor Alyssa B. Apsel	2012 – Present
Teaching Experience	
• Cornell ECE 2400 – Computer Systems Programming Lead Graduate Teaching Assistant	2017
• Cornell ECE 4750 – Computer Architecture Lead Graduate Teaching Assistant	2014
Cornell CURIE Academy     Lead Graduate Teaching Assistant	2014
• Cornell ENGRG 1060 – Explorations in Engineering Graduate Teaching Assistant	2013
Cornell ECE 4750 – Computer Architecture     Undergraduate Teaching Assistant	2011

## **Industry Experience**

	NVIDIA ASIC/VLSI Research Group, Austin, TX Graduate Research Intern	2017
	<b>Intel Many Integrated Core</b> , Hillsboro, OR Graduate Design and Validation Intern	2012
•	<b>Intel Many Integrated Core</b> , Hillsboro, OR Undergraduate Validation Intern	2011
Tes	st Chips and Prototyping	
Se	ee my research website for photos and details: http://www.csl.cornell.edu/~ctorng	
	Batten Research Group Test Chip 2 (BRGTC2) Task-Based Parallel Runtimes	2018
A CONTRACTOR OF THE PARTY OF TH	Pulse-Coupled Oscillator Synchronizer (PCOSYNC) Baseband Synchronizers for Internet of Things	2018
100000000000000000000000000000000000000	The Celerity RISC-V Tiered Accelerator Fabric (Celerity)  Methodologies for Rapid ASIC Design	2017
	Batten Research Group Test Chip 1 (BRGTC1) Python-Based Hardware Modeling	2016
	Dynamic Capacitance Sharing (DCS) Integrated Voltage Regulation	2014

## Media Coverage

- EETimes: 16 Views of Hot Chips '17, ASIC done in nine months for \$1.3M
  - https://www.eetimes.com/document.asp?doc\_id=1332192&page\_number=10

## **Journal Publications**

Top-tier architecture journals in this list IEEE MICRO
Top-tier circuits journals in this list IEEE TCAS I

- Scott Davidson, Shaolin Xie, **Christopher Torng**, Khalid Al-Hawaj, Austin Rovinski, Tutu Ajayi, Luis Vega, Chun Zhao, Ritchie Zhao, Steve Dai, Aporva Amarnath, Bandhav Veluri, Paul Gao, Anuj Rao, Gai Liu, Rajesh K. Gupta, Zhiru Zhang, Ronald G. Dreslinski, Christopher Batten, and Michael B. Taylor. "The Celerity Open-Source 511-Core RISC-V Tiered Accelerator Fabric: Fast Architectures and Design Methodologies for Fast Chips". *IEEE Micro Volume* 38(2):30–41, *Mar/Apr.* 2018 (*IEEE MICRO*). Special issue for top picks from Hot Chips 29.
- Ivan Bukreyev, **Christopher Torng**, Waclaw Godycki, Christopher Batten, and Alyssa Apsel. "Four Monolithically Integrated Switched-Capacitor DC-DC Converters with Dynamic Capacitance Sharing in 65-nm CMOS". *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems I* (**IEEE TCAS I**), PP(99):1-13. November 2017.

### **Conference Publications**

Top-tier architecture conferences in this list

Top-tier chip / design automation conferences in this list

DAC, HotChips

• Shunning Jiang, **Christopher Torng**, and Christopher Batten . "An Open-Source Python-Based Hardware Generation, Simulation, and Verification Framework". First Workshop on Open-Source EDA Technology held in conjunction with ICCAD-37 (WOSET). San Diego, CA. November 2018.

- Christopher Torng, Shunning Jiang, Khalid Al-Hawaj, Ivan Bukreyev, Berkin Ilbeyi, Tuan Ta, Lin Cheng, Julian Puscar, Ian Galton, and Christopher Batten. "A New Era of Silicon Prototyping in Computer Architecture Research". RISC-V Day Workshop held in conjunction with MICRO-51 (RISC-V Day). Fukuoka, Japan. October 2018.
- Brucek Khailany, Evgeni Krimer, Rangharajan Venkatesan, Jason Clemons, Joel Emer, Matthew Fojtik, Alicia Klinefelter, Michael Pellauer, Nathaniel Pinckney, Yakun Sophia Shao, Shreesha Srinath, Christopher Torng, Sam (Likun) Xi, Yanqing Zhang, Brian Zimmer. "A Modular Digital VLSI Flow for High-Productivity SoC Design". 55th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC). San Francisco, CA. June 2018.
- Ji Kim, Shunning Jiang, **Christopher Torng**, Moyang Wang, Shreesha Srinath, Berkin Ilbeyi, Khalid Al-Hawaj, Christopher Batten. "Using Intra-Core Loop-Task Accelerators to Improve the Productivity and Performance of Task-Based Parallel Programs". 50th IEEE/ACM Int'l Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO). Boston, MA. October 2017.
- Tutu Ajayi, Khalid Al-Hawaj, Aporva Amarnath, Steve Dai, Scott Davidson, Paul Gao, Gai Liu, Anuj Rao, Austin Rovinski, Ningxiao Sun, **Christopher Torng**, Luis Vega, Bandhav Veluri, Shaolin Xie, Chun Zhao, Ritchie Zhao, Christopher Batten, Ronald G. Dreslinski, Rajesh K. Gupta, Michael B. Taylor, Zhiru Zhang. "Experiences Using the RISC-V Ecosystem to Design an Accelerator-Centric SoC in TSMC 16nm". First Workshop on Computer Architecture Research with RISC-V (CARRV). Boston, MA. October 2017.
- Tutu Ajayi, Khalid Al-Hawaj, Aporva Amarnath, Steve Dai, Scott Davidson, Paul Gao, Gai Liu, Atieh Lotfi, Julian Puscar, Anuj Rao, Austin Rovinski, Loai Salem, Ningxiao Sun, Christopher Torng, Luis Vega, Bandhav Veluri, Xiaoyang Wang, Shaolin Xie, Chun Zhao, Ritchie Zhao, Christopher Batten, Ronald G. Dreslinski, Ian Galton, Rajesh K. Gupta, Patrick P. Mercier, Mani Srivastava, Michael B. Taylor, Zhiru Zhang. "Celerity: An Open Source RISC-V Tiered Accelerator Fabric". 29th Symposium on High Performance Chips (HotChips). Cupertino, CA. August 2017.
- **Christopher Torng**, Moyang Wang, Bharath Sudheendra, Nagaraj Murali, Suren Jayasuriya, Shreesha Srinath, Taylor Pritchard, Robin Ying, and Christopher Batten. "Experiences Using A Novel Python-Based Hardware Modeling Framework For Computer Architecture Test Chips". *Poster at the 28th Symposium on High Performance Chips* (HotChips Poster). Cupertino, CA. August 2016.
- **Christopher Torng**, Moyang Wang, and Christopher Batten. "Asymmetry-Aware Work-Stealing Runtimes". *43rd ACM/IEEE Int'l Symp. on Computer Architecture* (ISCA). Seoul, Korea. June 2016.
- Waclaw Godycki\*, **Christopher Torng**\*, Ivan Bukreyev, Alyssa Apsel, and Christopher Batten. "Enabling Realistic Fine-Grain Voltage Scaling with Reconfigurable Power Distribution Networks". *47th IEEE/ACM Int'l Symposium on Microarchitecture* (**MICRO**). Cambridge, UK. December 2014. (\* = equally contributing co-first authors)
- Ji Kim, **Christopher Torng**, Shreesha Srinath, Derek Lockhart, and Christopher Batten. "Microarchitectural Mechanisms to Exploit Value Structure in SIMT Architectures". 40th ACM/IEEE Int'l Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA). Tel Aviv, Israel. June 2013.

#### **Talks**

- "A New Era of Silicon Prototyping in Computer Architecture Research" October 2018 RISC-V Day Workshop held in conjunction with MICRO-51. Fukuoka, Japan.
- "Software, Architecture, and VLSI Co-Design for Task-Based Parallel Runtimes" October 2018
   Rising Stars in Computer Architecture (RISC-A) Workshop
   Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, GA.
- "Towards Rapid Chip Development with Celerity and BRGTC1"

  Invited talk at CMU Computer Architecture Lab (CALCM)

  Carnegie Mellon University. Pittsburgh, PA.

April 2018

• "Experiences Using the RISC-V Ecosystem October 2017 to Design an Accelerator-Centric SoC in TSMC 16nm"

CARRV: First Workshop on Computer Architecture Research with RISC-V. Boston, MA.

 "Celerity: An Open Source RISC-V Tiered Accelerator Fabric" Cornell Electron Devices Society. Ithaca, NY. September 2017

• "Asymmetry-Aware Work-Stealing Runtimes" ISCA: 43rd ACM/IEEE Int'l Symp. on Computer Architecture (ISCA-43). Seoul, Korea. June 2016

"Enabling Realistic Fine-Grain Voltage Scaling December 2014 with Reconfigurable Power Distribution Networks"
 MICRO: 47th IEEE/ACM Int'l Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO-47). Cambridge, UK.

• "On-Chip Reconfigurable Power Distribution Networks" Cornell STEM Graduate Student Summer Colloquium. Ithaca, NY.

July 2013

"Reconfigurable Power Distribution Networks for Embedded Multicore Processors" March 2013
 QInF: Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finals. Bridgewater, NJ.

#### Outreach

### • Cornell CURIE Academy

2014

Lead Graduate Teaching Assistant

The CURIE Academy is a one-week summer residential program organized by the Cornell Diversity Programs in Engineering for high school girls who excel in math and science, enjoy solving problems, and want to learn more about careers in engineering.

#### **Professional Activities**

Shadow PC Member for ASPLOS 2018
 Reviewer for IEEE TCAS I
 2016

### **My Open-Source Projects**

• The Modular VLSI Build System https://github.com/cornell-brg/alloy-asic 2018

#### Miscellaneous

• Music Director for FantAsia A Cappella at Cornell

2013 - 2015

• Hobbies: figure skating, singing a cappella, music composition and arrangement, piano

#### References

### • Christopher Batten (advisor)

Associate Professor of Electrical and Computing Engineering, Cornell University chatten@cornell.edu

### • Alyssa B. Apsel

Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Cornell University aba25@cornell.edu

## • Michael B. Taylor

Associate Professor of Electrical Engineering / Computer Science and Engineering, University of Washington prof.taylor@gmail.com

#### • Ronald G. Dreslinski

Assistant Professor of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, University of Michigan rdreslin@umich.edu

### • Brucek Khailany

Lead for the NVIDIA ASIC & VLSI Research Group, NVIDIA Research bkhailany@nvidia.com